A Finding Aid to the Paul Jenkins Papers, circa 1915-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, circa 1930-2010; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 9 Linear feet Box 1-9, Box 13
  - Unidentified Correspondence, circa 1944-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Inventories of Letters, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 38-41)
    (4 folders)
  - Inventories of Letters, 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Paul Jenkins to Norman Bluhm (ACCESS RESTRICTED), circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Writings, circa 1950-2003; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 9-10
  This series consists of miscellaneous writings by Paul Jenkins, two of his travel diaries, and the guest book for an exhibition of his work in Tokyo. Also found are a copy of Lili Krahmer Verame's China travel diary and the writings and research materials of others, including Simone Benmussa, Peter Brook, André Bruyère, Kenneth B. Sawyer, Frank Anderson Trapp, André Verdet, and Paul Veyne.
  - Paul Jenkins Travel Diary (China), 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Paul Jenkins Travel Diary (Russia and Paris), 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Writings by Paul Jenkins, circa 1950-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Paul Jenkins Tokyo Gallery Guestbook, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Verame, Lili (Krahmer), Travel Diary, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Benmussa, Simone, Writings, circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Brook, Peter, "Meetings with Remarkable Men" Script, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bruyère, André, Writings, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sawyer, Kenneth B., Writings, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Trapp, Frank Anderson, Writings and Research Materials, circa 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - Trapp, Frank Anderson, Writings and Research Materials, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Verdet, André, Writings, circa 1986-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Veyne, Paul, Writings, circa 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, A-F, circa 1964-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, H-M, circa 1952-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, O-W, circa 1959-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1944-1990; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 10
  This series contains bills, receipts, check registers, lists of expenses, lease documents, price lists, travel documents, taxes, and papers regarding Jenkins's rental property. Also included are a file on the New York University medal designed by Jenkins and a file concerning a Karl Prantl statue.
  - Bills and Receipts, 1953-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Book Project, circa 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
    (Includes correspondense with Lynd Ward and photographs from God's Man)
  - Check Register, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Check Register, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Expenses, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Film Projects, 1966-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Lease Documents, 1955-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - New York University Medal, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Prantl Statue, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
    (Includes correspondence and photographs regarding Karl Prantl statue)
  - Price Lists, circa 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Rental Property, 1948-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Taxes, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Travel, 1944-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Printed Material, circa 1952-2010; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 10-11
  Printed material event programs, guest lists, newsletters, bulletins, member reports, press releases, art exhibition announcements, and catalogs, concert and theater announcements and programs, miscellaneous materials regarding theater, college course announcements, news and magazine clippings, and obituaries and memorial announcements. Material primarily documents Jenkins's career as an artist and playwright.
  - College Course Announcements and Brochures, circa 1952-1953, 1988-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Concert and Theater Announcements, circa 1981-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Concert and Theater Programs, circa 1980-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Event Programs and Guest Lists, 1966-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, circa 1983-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, circa 1991-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Brochures, circa 1962-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Brochures, 1996-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Magazines, 1981-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Materials Regarding Theater, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, circa 1924, 1940-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, circa 1970-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, circa 1984-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, circa 2001-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, circa 2005-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Bulletins, and Member Reports, circa 1950-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries and Memorial Announcements (For Others), circa 1962-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries and Memorial Announcements (For Others), circa 2001-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, circa 1965-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1956-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Artwork, circa 1935-2007; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 11-12, OV 14
  This series contains miscellaneous sketches and collages by Paul Jenkins. Also found are are sketches, watercolors, and prints by other artists, such as Norman Bluhm, Denis Bowen, Thomas Erma, Pehr Hallsten, Matsumi "Mike" Kanemitsu, Sam Kaner, N. Hayden Stubbing, Yoshito Takahashi, Gérard Thalmann, André Verdet, and Jan Yoors, as well as 8 oversize mixed media sketches by Frank Prince of Jenkins's Meditation Mandala Sundial sculptures.
  - Paul Jenkins, circa 1935-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Denis Bowen, 1991-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Erma, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - André Verdet, 1963, 1984-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Artwork by Others, circa 1953-1998, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    (Includes artwork by Norman Bluhm, Pehr Hallsten, Matsumi "Mike" Kanemitsu, Sam Kaner, N. Hayden Stubbing, Yoshito Takahashi, Gérard Thalmann, Jan Yoors)
  - Oversized Artwork, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 14)
    (8 mixed media sketches by Frank Prince for Meditation Mandala Sundial)
- Photographs, circa 1940-1998; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 12
  Photographs depict Paul Jenkins in his studio, with family and friends, at an exhibition opening, at a ceremony at the National Museum of Wales, and sitting on a panel at the D.H. Lawrence Festival. Also found is a file on Piet Mondrian's exhibit, The Wall Works, and slides of André Bruyère and others.
  Of note are photographs of family and friends, including Esther Ebenhoe Jenkins, Alice Baber Jenkins, Karel Appel, Jean-Louis Barrault, Norman Bluhm, Stanley Boxer, Richard Burton, David Douglas Duncan, Zoe Dusanne, Thomas Erma, Ava Gardner, Françoise Gilot, Matsumi "Mike," Carole, and Bunshi Paul Kanemitsu, Grace Kelly, Georges Mathieu, Silvia Monfort, Philip Pavia, Frank Prince, Pierre Restany, Jean-Paul Riopelle, Alan Schneider, John Steinbeck, Lee Strasberg, Mark Tobey, and Jan Yoors.
  - Paul Jenkins in His Studio, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Paul Jenkins with Others, circa 1943-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
    (Includes photographs with Jean-Louis Barrault, Matsumi "Mike" Kanemitsu, Philip Pavia)
  - Paul Jenkins at World of Phenomena Exhibit, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Paul Jenkins at National Museum of Wales Ceremony, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
    (Includes photographs with Richard Burton, photographs of donated bronze head of Dylan Thomas by David Slivka and Ibram Lassaw)
  - Paul Jenkins at D.H. Lawrence Festival, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Jenkins Family, circa 1940-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Alice Baber Jenkins, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Esther Ebenhoe Jenkins, circa 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Norman Bluhm, circa 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Thomas Erma, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
    (Includes photograph with John Steinbeck)
  - Françoise Gilot, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Bunshi Paul Kanemitsu, 1974-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Matsumi "Mike" and Carole Kanemitsu, circa 1958-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Piet Mondrian, The Wall Works, 1984-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
    (Includes 3 35-mm color slides, 3 photographs, and 3 color ektachromes)
  - Frank Prince, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Photos of Others, A-G, circa 1953, 1984-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
    (Includes photographs of Karel Appel, Stanley Boxer, David Douglas Duncan, Zoe Dusanne, Ava Gardner)
  - Miscellaneous Photos of Others, K-W, circa 1942, 1955-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    (Includes photographs of Grace Kelly, Georges Mathieu, Silvia Monfort, Pierre Restany, Jean-Paul Riopelle, Alan Schneider, Lee Strasberg, Mark Tobey, Jan Yoors)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Slides, André Bruyère, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Slides, Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1960-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)